Hello Andri Hello, Norway
Здравствуйте Андри Здравствуйте Норвегия
or Finland, you somehow have both of them And
или Финляндия у вас как-то и тот и тот А
this is just a branded cap on Papi
это ж это кепка просто брендовая на Папи
and I live in Finland Yes, I understand, and the text is
а живу в Финляндии Да понял а текст
something behind
что-то там зади
OTS, well, representatives of the Zenit club just meet here Yes, this is
ОТС ну здесь встречаются просто ну
about them
Зенит Да это про них
not these football movements, this is of course
не эти футбольные движи это конечно
interesting, yes Well, yes,
интересно да Ну
you’ve been living in Finland for a long time since the fifteenth year. Now you’re
Финляндии с пятнадцатого года Вот вы уже
almost Finn. Well, I’m Karel, as if I’m not that
почти Фин Ну я Карел как бы я не то что
I’m Finn, I’m Finn, but well, you’re an ethnic Korela,
я Фин я Фин а ну вы этнический Корела
lived in Ukraine, but it turns out no Russia
жили в Украине да получается нет Россия
And this is you  just a Dynamo fan from Russia,
А это вы просто фанат Динамо из России
yes. Well, I’ve been involved in kickboxing since childhood
да Ну я занимался кикбоксингом с детства
and participated, and as if we had a
и участвовал и как бы у нас был клуб
Dynamos club, I played for it. And I thought
динамос я вот за него выступал А я думал
it was Dynamo
это Динамо
Kiev. Listen, let’s say we have
Киев Слушай ну допустим у нас фанаты
Dynamo fans divided into two clubs, oh, into two,
Динамо делятся на два клуба ой на два
two sectors, there are  who, let’s say,
два сектора есть кто допустим
supports the letter, that is, for me, the
поддерживает литеру то есть для меня
letter Dynamo Yes, this is the letter e, it doesn’t
литера Динамо Да это буква э вот без
matter there Kiev speaker there is
разницы там Киевский динамик там
some kind of
какой-нибудь
Minsk Dresden Dynamo and Dynamo That
Минский дрезденский Динамо и Динамо То
is, I support all of these Yes, as it were,
есть я поддерживаю все эти Да как бы дви
Dynamo And you, where you
Динамо А ты сре сам откуда
come from Well sorted the city Well  like with
родом Ну сортовала город Ну типа с
this part occupied by the Soviet
оккупированной этой части советским
Union, yes it turns out Well yes yes yes it’s
союзом да получается Ну да да да
interesting because there’s a scoop to
интересно во потому что там ж совок
assimilate a lot of people there
ассимилировать много поводил туда людей
also from Ukraine from Russia like no no
также из Украины из России типа нене не
I by the way can tell you about this moment in
я кстати могу рассказать про этот момент
history that they Yes they are just after the
истории что они Да они просто после
war there are a lot of Karelians  there were Vepsians and there were
войны много карелов там вепсов да там
Karelians, Estonians, there were already a lot of people
карелов эстонцев там уже много людей
living there, of different
жило различных этих
nationalities,
вот народностей
many of them went to Finland. Well, who went to
многие уехали в Финляндию Ну кто в
Estonia, who managed to dump everything, dumped everything and the
Эстонию кто успел свалить все свалили и
Soviets, in short, in order to
совки короче дабы это всё население
somehow revive the entire population. They opened there, like, yes,
как-то возродить Они открыли там типа да
such a population-based program, in short. Yes,
такую популяционно короче программу Да
and everyone who came there,
вот и все кто туда приезжал
imagine, let’s say there’s a person from Ukraine
представляете там допустим с Украины
there, he came from the south. There to
человек там он с юга приехал Там на
work, they went crazy from our
заработки они сходили с ума от нашей
midges from the gadflies and no one took root,
мошкары от оводов и никто не прижился
everyone left, in short, back to this and it
все уезжали короче в это обратно и
turns out that after two years this program
получается год через два эта программа
was reset and they did very  such a vile
обнулись и они делали очень такой подлый
step remained Well, not all people could
шаг оставались Ну не все же люди могли
leave, again those who left were those who had
уехать опять же уезжали кто имел
some kind of resource, money,
какой-то там ресурс деньги возможность
some kind of opportunity Yes, and they did as they
кло какую-нибудь Да и они сделали как
found relatives, let’s say
они находили родственников допустим у
I have my grandfather Yes, he lived in Finland,
меня есть дед мой Да он в Финляндии жил
he left But  then he returned Yes,
он уехал Вот но потом вернулся Да потому
because he had an aunt Well, My aunt
что тётки у него была тётя Ну Моя тётя
It turns out from his grandfather Yes, his sister is his
Это получается по деду Да его сестра
grandmother So they threatened, that is, they
вот бабушка Вот они и угрожали то есть
sent him a letter there, in short, to
ему направили письмо туда короче в
Finland and wrote You have a year
Финляндию и написали У тебя есть год
to return home,
чтоб вернуться обратно домой не
we will not return to your ancestors
вернёшься мы твоих предков куда-нибудь
we’ll take them somewhere Well, as the rules didn’t take them away,
увезём Ну как правила их не увозили их
well, in short, the same thing happened in Chechnya,
короче ну как вот в Чечне такое же
that is, who was the unwanted
подобное было то есть кто был неугодный
Russian terror? Well, 90 percent of the
террор российский Да вот и процентов 90
people returned back inger molansov
людей вернулось обратно ингер молан сов
of various kinds, there were a lot of people returning
различных там полно вернулось людей
back to their lands where they were  lived in order to
обратно на свои земли где они жили дабы
preserve, as it were, with us, and so everything all our
сохранить как бы у нас и так все всю
lives, as if we have such a territory as
жизнь как бы у нас такая территория как
Ukraine, you have the north-west,
вот Украина у вас так у нас северо-запад
here we always have Swedes and Finns,
у нас тут у нас вечно там и шведы и фины
and there, in short, there are Swedes, in short, Vikings
и там короче там шведа ны короче Викинги
there are Russians  There, in general, it was such a
там русские там в общем такое
troubled place and our brother got it
неспокойное место и доставалось нашему
all the time, and we
брату постоянно а мы же колхозники в
were mostly collective farmers, and how were the people of nature
основном да как были люди природы там
living there in their own settlements? We and now
жили своими там поселениями мы и сейчас
also
также
have small settlements, such as, well,
есть маленькие поселения у на есть такие
farmsteads, we call them Yes, in
как бы ну хутора мы их называем Да по
our opinion, but as  for example, this is with the
наше а как например вот это с языком
native language of the Karelians now in the region Well,
родным у карелов сейчас в краях Ну вот у
I had, so to speak, Why did I start
меня была так скажем Почему я стал уже
thinking about Finland later, I
потом думать про Финляндию у меня
had, so to speak, article 282 burning of
была так сказать статья 282 сжигание
hatred and extremism like yes yes We
ненависти ти экстремизм типа да да Мы
created, so to speak, a school for studying the
создали так скажем школу по изучению
Karelian language in  Karelia and the
карельского языка в Карелии и
comrades of Phobos Atat came to us,
к нам пришли товарищи фобоса атата вы
what are you doing because the revival of
что се творите потому что Возрождение
the language in Karelia Well, what will he do to himself?
языка в Карелии Ну что он с собой
Well, nationally, some kind of
сделает Ну национально какую-то там
Ascension Yes, identification is this,
Вознесение Да идентификация это это
Russia is just afraid, therefore this is and this is more
Россия как раз боится поэтому это а это
dangerous such a Hot place there are few of us Well  it’s like they’re
опаснее такое Горячее место нас мало Ну
all so hot, they’re all healthy, they’re
как бы такие все горячие все здоровые
so two-meter tall. Guys, that is, let’s say.
такие двухметровые Мужики то есть дасть
We can, as it were, work with this poker
Можем как бы с этой с кочергой
in the field. And we can even take a sword in our hands, and
работать на поле А можем и меч в руки
there, well, I’m speaking relatively speaking. That is,
взять да там ну условно говорю То есть
all the men are like that. Healthy Here we have
такие все мужики Здоровые У нас вот
And thereby, as it were,
И тем самым как бы
well  Our kind of
ну наш как бы
person was, as it were, again down there, in
человек был как бы опять туда вот вниз
short, lowered, that is, the Russian language
короче спущен да то есть русский язык
Again became, as it were, such a language of prestige of
Опять стал как бы таким языком престижа
our republic, such situations in
нашей республи такие ситуаци в
Bastana, the rdki language also from schools is almost
бастане рдки язык тоже со школ почти
complete, but they understand it easier,
окончательно но у них проще понимаешь у
they still have a language  mothers, that is,
них всё-таки есть язык матери то есть
they communicate in it, as it were, and
они общаются на нём как бы ти и
the number is greater, yes
количество больше да да Вот то есть
yes, that is, somehow, yes, that is, they still have
как-то да то есть у них там всё-таки
millions of people there, as it were, but I don’t know us here,
миллионы народ как бы а нас тут не знаю
there are 50 thousand, God forbid there will be
там тысяч 50 дай Бог там на наберётся
many Karelians there  now they call themselves
Многие же карелы теперь называют себя
Russians, it’s not just the Karelians,
русскими ещё так это не только карелы э
uh, they say there in Russia, 140
вот говорят там в России 140 там
people there, there are 100-something million
населения там 100 с чем-то миллионов
Russians. Where did so many of them come from? They
русских Откуда их столько взялось
enrolled the Karelians there; they enrolled the Mari;
записали Карел туда записали марийцев
they recorded everyone like this;
записали всех вот так позаписи ээ и при
you're
Союзе также было потому что если ты
Russian, somehow she was prestigious, that
русский как-то она было престижний то
is, you can't say there's a Mari, for example,
есть не скажешь там мариец да например
or uh, during the Soviet era there was something else like that. What
или э при совке было ещё такое Ты какого
year were you born, by the way, eighty-
года рождения кстати восемьдесят
eighth? And I'm eighty-first, I'm still 10
восьмого А я восемьдесят первой я ещё 10
years old when I found the Sovka, I remember there were, uh,
лет Совка застал я помню были вот ээ
jokes Yes, there were special jokes
анекдоты Да специально ходили анекдоты
about everyone there about the Armenians about the Georgians about the
про всех там про армян про грузин про
Moldovans the Ukrainians Chu All about xn I know
молдован украинцев чу Все я про хн знаю
the plague of the Chukhonts for her Yes, everyone yes Chukhonts
чуму чухонца для ней Да все да чухонцы
They are like that, well, Chukhonets Chukhonka, in short, that’s what they
Они так ну чухонец чухонка короче они же
say Yes Like yes n for everything I’m communicating
так и говорят Да Типа да н на на всё вот
here I’m communicating here for example
вот общаюсь я вот общаюсь здесь например
who has this extension? Yes, it’s
у кого есть это вот расширение Да там
like where the person is from there, he’s like oh
типа откуда человек там он такой о
Chukhonian like yes no Fin there not Karel there
чухонец типа да не Фин там не Карел там
or there Hello ska oh Chukhonian there
или там Здравствуйте ска о чухонец там
you know this guy appeared there and I
знаешь появился такой типа вот а я с
usually like to ask around with them
такими обычно люблю поспрашивать у них
Well I think that too  as if it’s possible in Nats
Ну я думаю это тоже как бы можно в наты
Yes,
Да вот
this is how to use such a kind of population I
это использовать такую как бы популяцию
ask And where do the Russians have a republic? I say, I’m
спрашиваю А где у русских республика Я
Karel. For example, let’s say I
говорю я вот Карел Например у меня
have in Russia, that is, there is a
допустим в России да то есть есть свой
subject of the Federation there, and it’s like a
субъект Федерации там да как бы
Korelian republic, I say, you
корельская республика я говорю вот ты
call yourself Russian  yes And where is your
называешь себя русским да А где у тебя
Russian republic And that’s it And now it’s
республика русская И всё И вот троить
starting to triple in my region there I have a region there I have there
начинает у меня там область у меня там
zy well in general there yes
край у меня там зй ну в общем там да вот
that’s all I know how cool
это вот всё я я знаешь как их классно
I trolled them they say like we don’t have a
троллил они говорят типа у нас нет
Republic We are the ones  that's all I say so ri It
Республики Мы те всё я говорю так ри Это
turns out that Russians and Gypsies are
получается что русские и цыгане - это
two nationalities in the Russian Federation
две народности в Российской Федерации
that do not have their own republic and so
которые не имеют своей республики и так
undermining wait wait if I clarify for you By the way
подрыва подожди подожди если тебя уточню
I have friends here Yes the
Кстати у меня есть друзья здесь Да
Gypsies in Finland They call themselves
цыгане в Финляндии Они называют себя
Romei Romanians Roly Roma PAZ Yes  that is,
ромеи румыны ролы Роме ПАЗ Да вот то
as if they still have, even
есть как бы у них всё-таки есть даже у
they even have their own republic, there is some kind of
них даже республика своя есть какая-то
original homeland, yes, that is, this is
изначальная Родина да то есть это
Romania not not not Romania is not their
Румыния не не не Румыния не есть их
homeland Well, I don’t know That is, I talked with
родина Ну я не знаю То есть я общался со
my gypsies, he says here  like
своими цыганами говорит у нас типа
Romania there, they are with Romania there, in
Румыния там ти они с румынией там в
general, that is, they even have some kind of
общем то есть даже у них есть какая-то
Motherland, that is,
Родина то есть да ромеи
yes, the Romans, but the Russians have what they have, he
вот вот а у русских что у них есть он
says Russia Russia is in Greek
говорит Россия Россия - это по-гречески
Russia I say this, and what does Russia have to do with it?
Русь Я говорю так Причём здесь Русь
and you
говорю и ты
say you lived all your life in Muscovy, lived
говорю ты жил всю жизнь в московии жил
how Russia appeared here, I say Russians were
как тут Русь появилась я говорю русскими
the first people to call these
раньше всех называли изначально вот этих
ethnic Ukrainians, these were Russians of
этнических украинцев это русские были
Rus Da Ru. It’s just that later, when Muscovy
Руси Да ру Просто потом когда Московия
captured the Russians, they began to call all
захватила русских стали называть всех
these Russians; then there was no National at all,
этих русскими г не было тогда вообще
so they  Well, even Look, even
Националь так они Ну даже Смотри даже
when Muscovy captured under
когда Московия захватила при императоре
this emperor Peter Yes, when he was the Empire Yes,
там этом Петре Да когда он Империю Да
they didn’t call themselves Russians Yes, that’s where the
они не называли себя русскими Да вот там
Moscow state became the Russian
Московское государство стало Российской
Empire Yes, there are different nationalities there In short,
империей Да там разные народности Короче
okay,
ладно
it’s good there, even just even two villages
хорошо там даже просто даже два села
nearby were, for example,
каких-нибудь рядом находились например
there  even the languages ​​were different back then, it’s
там даже языки различались тогда вообще
not even clear how people even
даже непонятно как там вообще люди
existed there on the same collective farm, they
существовали в одном колхозе
spoke there through Oh another through and
разговаривали там через О другое через и
for example there were dialects there. You know how
например там диалекты были Знаешь как
interesting it is they start talking there, here
интересно они там начинают говорит вот у
you are, even in short there, a dude like from
вас там вы даже короче там чувак типа с
Kharkov won’t understand the dude there
Харькова не будет понимать чувака там
in short, from Transcarpathia or from Lvov. But
короче с Закарпатья или со Львова Так
they don’t [ __ ] understand that if they
они же блин не понимают что у них если
watch a non-television language, they
смотреть не телевизионный язык так а
’ll go to the Vologda region. Yes, and they’ll go,
заедут в вологодскую область Да и заедут
for example, somewhere damn it to the Krasnodar
например куда-то блин в Краснодарский
region, there will be a completely different dialect, it will be absolutely the same,
край там совсем другой говор будет
absolutely not, well, you
абсолютно также абсолютно не ну там
see how  In the Vologda region after
видишь как Вологодской области после
the war there were a lot of refugees there. Why
войны там же много было беженцев Почему
exactly did a lot of Ukrainians come from the
именно оть стали много украинцев
direction of Vologda and
бы да было сз в сторону Вологды и
that’s why they started moving? It seems to me
поэтому стали о Мне кажется
that because, well, my relatives worked there at
что потому что ну мои родственники там в
one time and lived in Murmansk.
своё время работали И жили в Мурманске
Yes, and why did they also appear in Murmansk?
Да и почему в Мурманске также появился
talk about we have the same thing there Well, Murmansk
говор о у нас там то же Ну Мурманске
Kondopoga there are a lot of Ukrainians there and
Кондопога очень много украинцев там да
a lot of them were brought not Kanda Poga -
очень много по завозили не Канда пога -
after all, this is Karelia, this is
это всё-таки это Карелия это
Petrozavodsk Murmansk, it’s higher there, it’s not
Петрозаводск Мурманск это выше туда не
good, and in KAPO and Murmansk they brought
ну гово и в КАПО и в Мурманск поволи
a lot of Ukrainians That’s why  that, as
очень много украинцев Вот потому что как
it were, dialectics in terms of about there be, this is, in
бы диалектика в плане о там бы ть это в
principle, a normal system in terms of this is
принципе нормальная система в плане вот
North By the way, Kondopoga is
это вот Северо Кстати а Кондопога - это
Korelian,
корельский
in general it’s correct to call it konda poga konda
вобще правильно назвать кон конда пога
poga Uh-huh And what does this mean konda
конда пога Угу А что это означает конда
- this is Bear poga - this is the corner of konda poga
- это Медведь пога - это угол конда пога
Bear's corner is cool, let's say
Медвежий угол прикольно также допустим
Kanda is Kandalaksha is a city in general in
Канда есть Кандалакша есть город вообще
Karelian in Finnish it's in shackles, also
по-карельски по-фински это кандалах тоже
like Bear Bay Yes, it's
типа как медвежий залив Да
cool That is, well, many people
прикольно Такое то есть ну многие этого
don't know this from Russians, as in asking the
не знают у русских как во спроси
etymology what Moscow taka means there In
этимологии что означает там Москва
short, I don't know anything here  if we
така Короче ничего не знаю вот если мы
look at a city for example Zhitomir Zhitomir
смотрим город например Житомир Житомир
everything is clear, lifelike about Moscow about Moscow I’ll
всё понятно жито про Москву про Москву
tell you I won’t distract you anymore
тебе расскажу я не буду тебя больше
about Moscow there
отвлекать про Москву там же так
were also such Finno-Ugric peoples
находились же такие народы фино угорские
as Erzya and Moksha, and the Mordovians
как эрзя и мокша ну и мордовцы там тоже
were also present there Well, in Moscow itself there
присутствовали Ну в самой Москве не не
weren’t no  it was they further were were were
было это они дальше были были были были
right that's right that's exactly why I
были прямо вот прямо вот именно почему я
say that in our Karelian
говорю что у нас допустим в карельском
language and in Finnish and in Estonian the concept of
языке и в Финском и в эстонском понятие
Earth is ma Yes it indicates and it is
Земля - это ма Да оно указывает и оно
permissible there esti ma somi ma Yes there kala kala
допустим там эсти ма соми ма Да там кала
ma  yes, that is, in short, that is, everywhere there is an
кала ма да то есть короче То есть везде
Earth, that is, some kind of area, and the
ма Земля то есть какой-то участок а у
IOC had it a little differently, they had it
МОК было немножко по-другому у них это
all, the Earth was designated mo, they had and
всё Земля обозначалась мо у них было и у
in our language, as a rule, any words are
нас как правило в языке любые слова
so simple Yes, they were called according to the
такие простые Да они назывались по
natural one, for example  there is an infant,
природному например есть ребёнок грудной
it is called uaa Oddly enough, uaa
он называется уаа Как ни странно уаа Да
Yes ua uaa is an infant in
уа у уаа это грудной ребёнок
Karelian in Finnish
по-карельски по-фински
and a swamp or a frog is the quo Got it So
а болото или лягушка это кво Понял Вот и
we connect these two words, that is, Mo
мы связываем эти два слова то есть Мо
Iqua the essence is that the most important thing is that
иква суть суть в том что самое основное
it  all these are not Slavic words
что это всё не славянские слова
you understand. So I say to the Russians.
понимаешь Вот я я россияну говорю Вот
Take Ternopil thorns Pol
возьми Тернополь терновое Поль
to Zhitomir presses there is the sun somehow it’s clear yes.
во Житомир жими есть ВС както понятно да
And when I ask him what
А когда его спрашиваю что там например
Ryazan or
Рязань означает или
Arzamas means there, for example, I don’t know even Murmansk is the same
Арзамас не знаю даже вот Мурманск тот же
they sun Murmansk Murmansk there they say Yes
они ВС Мурманск Мурманск там говорят Да
I say  that Murmansk was a settlement of
я говорю что Мурманск это было поселение
Norwegians Well, at that time the settlement was
норвежцев Ну на то время поселение было
hostile Daho vono
враждебно дахо воно
city of some kind there Demons in short there are
город какие-нибудь там Бесы короче там
Vikings Yes there with weapons and They went
викингов ские Да там с оружием и Ходили
to the city of Kola there they massacred the people there they
в город Колу там вырезали народ там
stole, now it’s called Murmansk
воровали вот теперь это Мурманск
Yes why did they put it What
называется Да почему поставили Как
was the name  the first name of the novels in
название было первое название романов на
Murmansk is supposedly the Romanovs, yes, like in
мурмане якобы Романовы да типа на
Murmansk, like yes, like, in short, they
мурмане типа да типа короче они там всех
supposedly captured everyone there like that, and now they have
якобы захватили вот так вот а теперь они
turned it into Murmans Murmans Listen, the whole chat here is
перели в мурманс мурманс Слушай тут чат
asking you to ask whose
весь весь просят спросить у тебя чей
Crimea they can’t understand, whose is it all
Крым бо не могут понять ти чей всё
guys Calm down  ok I think Damn, I
ребята Успокойтесь нормально Я думаю
still don’t understand,
Блин что ещё не понимаю
of course, people with Yes, everything is fine for you,
конечно у людей с Да хорошо всё вам
great good luck Yes, so that the cockatiels also have
огромное удачи Да чтобы и кореллам тоже
their own independent state Yes, at
своё независимое государство Да на бы
least to return to Finland And there everything is already
хотя бы Финляндию вернуться А там уже
fine,
нормально всё
that’s how tsikavo tsikavo yes dosy
хоро вот так цикаво цикаво да досы
tsikavo I love zust representatives in the vestry
цикаво люблю зуст представникив ризных
national minorities and dosit SDO
национальных меншин прич до досить СДО
Lyudina Yes, not just there Yes, I’m Karel like
Людина Да не просто там Да я Карел типа
I’m there I went and whiz Toto Lyudina
я там Поехал да кудись Тото Людина
organized there the instillation of the Karelian
организовала там вивчення карельской
language in herself in the Fatherland in Russia Yes x
мовы в себе на батькивщини в Росии Да х
for the prize of the FSB Toto dosit tsikawi history
за прису ФСБ Тото досить цикави истории
Yes obvyazkovo we’ll put it out once with m karem
Да обовязково выставим раз с м карем
dosa  tsikavo and everyone who watches us
досы цикаво и всем кто нас смотрит
from Russia from the conquered peoples of Russia
из России из покорённых народов России
Yes, everything can be changed with the language
Да всё можно изменить с языковым
issue, everything can be changed, I often
вопросом всё всё можно изменить часто
hear that for example,
слышу что например вот всё уже башкор
we won’t really restore the Bashkor language because there are
язык мы не восстановим толком потому что
few native speakers. There’s something shorter, people
мало носителей Там что-то короче люди
already speak Russian  They say a lot there, the
уже по-русски много говорят там у
Mari have an even worse situation, it’s all [ __ ].
марийцев ещё хужа ситуация это всё фигня
I’ll tell you what. When I was
Я вам вот что скажу Когда я был
little in the USSR, uh, 10 years old, I was still
маленький при СССР ээ 10 лет я ещё от
studying in the USSR; in our city there were two
учился в СССР у нас в городе было две
Ukrainian schools only Yes, and the rest
украинских школы только Да а остальное
was all 28 in my opinion Yes  Russian
всё было 28 по-моему Да российских
Russian speakers Yes, everything tried to dominate there
русскоязычных Да всё старалось там
Russian language Russian language nothing for 30
русский язык русский язык ничего за 30
years of Independence they shifted everything in the other
лет Независимости сместили всё в другую
direction Yes, as soon as your peoples
сторону Да как только ваши народы
gain independence Yes, you can
обретут независимость Да так и сможете
develop your culture, your language, here are the
развивать свою культуру свой язык вот
Kazakhs, yes Kazakhstan lives Independently, all
казахи да Казахстан живёт Независимо всё
Kazakh songs Kazakh culture is
казахские песни казахская культура
Kazakh in general  everything is cool, yes Children, there
казахска вообще всё круто да Дети он в
is an international
Алматы проводится международная
Olympiad in Almaty Yes, in physics, mathematics,
олимпиада такая Да по физике математике
computer science, they do it in Kazakh, too;
информатике на казахском тоже они делают
children study in Kazakh, they have no
дети учатся на казахском у них без
problems. Why can they do it in Turkish, but for
проблем Почему на турецком могут да А
example, in Bashkor they can’t, that’s
например на башкор ском не могут вот
why, uh, as one
поэтому Ээ как говорил один Классик
Ukrainian classic, Bori, said  That you will overcome yes Bori you will overcome uh I
украинский Бори Та поборете да Бори
especially want to express my
поборете ээ особенно хочу высказать
support now Sakha yaku there we are watching
поддержку сейчас Саха яку тамм смотрим
you uh the events that are happening in your country
вас э события которые у вас происходят
Yes how the Russians want to curl yours Your
Да как [__] хочет завить ваши ваш
cinema Yes the national one which
кинематограф Да национальный который
promotes national meanings You are
национальные смыслы продвигает Э вы
handsome and Sakha I
красавчики и Саха Я
think it has something to do with that
думаю причём с тем с той динамикой
population dynamics  Yes, the outflow of this was brought in
населения Да оттока вот этого завезён
with the scoop of the
при совке
uh non-local population Yes, and increasing
ээ не местного населения Да и повышения
part of the uh autochthonous population, you
части ээ автохтонное населения у вас всё
will succeed, subscribe to my Telegram
всё получится подпишись на мий Telegram
directly at once ovin and
прямо зараз овин а
popk tse even more and more politely YouTube
попк це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube
drives us through Scar Georgi into those bans
загоняет нас через Скар георги в те бан
and even more richly video  I don’t show people
и дуже багато вдео не показую людям
constantly I don’t show information about streams
вчасно не показуе информация про стримы
in order for me to write Mali operative
тому для того щоб ми Мали оперативный
link directly for apok there in
звязок пишиться прямо за а пок там в
telegra okm vdeo ezh tsikava and korisna
телегра окм вдео ще теж цикава и корисна
information and we are guilty of you trimati lean
информация и мы повинни з вами тримати
operative link
постный оперативный звязок
independantly in that chi show you the process
незалежно в того чи покаже вам проце
YouTube  Glory to Ukraine
YouTube Слава Украине
subscribe
подпишись